Guide to the Hough family genealogy, 1865-1954.
Hough family genealogy, 1865-1954.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hough family genealogy, 1865-1954.
2023
Hough family.
1.4 cubic ft.
Genealogical charts, correspondence, publications, and other material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Genealogical charts of the descendants of William Hough, who came to America in 1640, and file cards which contain military service and vital records of Hough men who served in the French and Indian War, American Revolution, War of 1812, Mexican War, Civil War, and Spanish American War; and genealogical correspondence among members and various branches of the family.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Genealogical charts (ca. 60 items) of the descendants of William Hough, who came to America in 1640, and file cards (341 items) which contain military service and vital records of Hough men who served in the French and Indian War, American Revolution, War of 1812, Mexican War, Civil War, and Spanish American War, both sets compiled by Elida C. Hough; and genealogical correspondence among members and various branches of the family (1912-1954). Also, biographical and genealogical material pertaining to Franklin B. Hough, a forester.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hough family.; Hough, Elida Crofoot, 1863-1926.; Hough, Franklin Benjamin, 1822-1885.; Hough, William.
Subjects:
Foresters.
Places:
United States--History--French and Indian War, 1755-1763.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.; United States--History--War of 1812.; Mexican War, 1846-1848.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Spanish-American War, 1898.
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.; Vital statistics records.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Two volumes entitled Washingtoniana, vol. I and II by Franklin B. Hough; vol. I - 272 pp., vol. II - 304 pp. Published by W. Elliot Woodward - Roxbury, Mass., 1865. (Box 1)
  The volumes contain an account of the funeral honors paid the memory of George Washington and a list of the tracts and volumes printed upon the occasion. A catalogue of the medals commemorating the event are included. NOTE: Unbound, uncut.
  [The volumes arrived in a wrapper bearing the following legend:
  "F.B. Hough - Washingtoniana 2 vol. - 1 set of 91 quartos & of 6 on Whatman paper - Gift of Helen Y. Hough, - 2227 - 20th St., N.W., Washington 9, D.C." (granddaughter of F.B. Hough)]
- Letters in white legal size envelope written by Mrs. Elizabeth Keever Hough-Huff genealogy. (Box 1)
  - to Mr. Lawrence Cooper - 1 sheet (2 pp.), Oct. 22, 1934
  - to Dear Mr. Hough - 2 sheets (4 pp.), Nov. 7, 1934
  - to Mr. Lawrence C. Hough - 1 sheet (2 pp.), Nov. 18, 1934
  - to Dear Mr. Hough - 2 sheets (4 pp.), Nov. 21, 1934
  - to Mr. Lawrence Cooper Hough - 1 sheet (2 pp.), Dec. 18, 1934
- Photograph - Joseph H. Hough of Connecticut. (Box 1)
- Genealogy of Hough family (on blueprint type paper) starting with 1st generation in U.S. (1683-) (Box 1)
- A series of letters between various segments of the family re: genealogy, 1912-1954. (Box 1)
- Three packets of file cards - each card bears the name of a member of the Hough family and some genealogical dates on the individual. The cards seem to be divided into French and Indian War, Revolution, and Civil War periods. Also, Mexican War, War of 1812, and Spanish-American War. (Box 1)
- 56 sheets - genealogical charts on the Hough family. MSS. Date from 1780 or earlier; detailed. (Box 1)
- The Cornellian Council Bulletin, Jan. 1931, Vol. 16, No. 4. (Box 1)
- One empty large brown envelope - word "blueprints" in lower left corner - postmarked Chi., III. (Box 1)
- Genealogy of the Killam Family 1597-1902, Nelson C. Killam, Publisher, 603 W. Lexington Street, Baltimore, Maryland. (Box 1)
- Hough, Helen Yale; Descendants of Franklin B. Hough; a manuscript and a carbon copy of typescript, Oct. 1969.
- Hough, Elmer; Hough Genealogy; Tuttle Publishing Co., Inc., Rutland, Vermont.
- Hosmer, Ralph S.; Franklin B. Hough, Father of American Forestry. North Country Life; Ogdensburg, New York: vol. 6, no. 3, summer of 1952. (Box 1)
- Stiles, Henry R.; "Memorial Sketch of Franklin B. Hough"; New York Genealogical and Biographical Record; The Society; New York, Apr. 1886; Vol. 17, no. 2. (Box 1)
- Guthrie, Laurence C.; "Franklin B. Hough"; Union Alumni Monthly; Vol. 16, no. 2; Union College, Schenectady, New York; Dec. 1926. (Box 1)
- "Franklin B. Hough - A Tribute," American Forestry; Vol. 28, no. 343, Washington, D.C., July 1922. (Box 1)
- Daily Journals of Elida C. Hough Jan. 1, 1882-Nov. 18, 1916, Apr. 26, 1918-Sept. 7, 1926, 55 vols. (Box 2)